

CONTACT

- ISTANBUL/TURKEY
- emir.tuna44@gmail.com e.korkmaz2018@gtu.edu.tr
- +905334811004
- https://www.linkedin.com
 /in/emir-tuna-korkmaz5334811004/
- https://github.com/emirtu naa

EDUCATION

Gebze Technical University

September 2018 - July 2023 **Bachelor of Science in**

Mechanical Engineering

GPA: 3.16

Thesis: Artificial Intelligence Enabled Heat Sink Design for Additive Manufacturing

SKILLS

- • • Abagus
- • • Python
- • • Solidworks
- • • Catia V5
- • • Hypermesh
- • • Artificial Intelligence
- • • Matlab
- • • nTopology

LANGUAGES

- • • Turkish (Native)
- • • English (B2+)
- • • German (A2)

CERTIFICATES

- Algorithmic Engineer
 Certificate by Hyperganic
 - Innovation of Sustainable
- Aviation Challenge Certificate by General Electric

Emir Tuna Korkmaz

MECHANICAL ENGINEER

ABOUT

I am a recent graduate with a bachelor's degree in mechanical engineering from Gebze Technical University with a strong passion for applying artificial intelligence and additive manufacturing to address engineering challenges. I have a keen interest in areas such as thermal analysis, explicit analysis, topology optimization, and the application of statistical tools to enhance engineering solutions. While I have a keen interest in these topics, I remain open to exploring innovative and research-based areas in the field.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Enau GmbH - Functional Safety Consultant

March 2023 - September 2023

- Strong background in A-SPICE, ISO 26262, and knowledge of automotive standards and regulations.
- Proficiency in project management methodologies, including Six Sigma, Kanban, and Scrum.
- Primarily served to TOGG projects.

Siemens - Strategic Procurement Working Student

October 2022 - March 2023

• Actively involved in the management of contract agreements, the evaluation of suppliers, and the identification of new suppliers for Siemens.

Siemens - Real Estate Internship

July 2022 - August 2022

• Gained experience in project management, sustainability, HVAC, batteries, renewable energy, and their industrial applications.

AKIM Metal - Manufacturing Internship

August 2021 -September 2021

- Had the chance to get detailed information about machining and casting manufacturing methods.
- Gained information about measuring techniques, measuring tools, testing, and analysis of manufactured parts.

ACTIVITIES

Article on Artificial Intelligence Enabled Heat Sink Design for Additive Manufacturing

August 2023 - In Progress

• Decided to transform our thesis topic into an article with the goal of enhancing the heat sink's thermal performance and efficiency through additive manufacturing techniques, AI-driven optimization, and statistical approaches.

TEKNOFEST Artificial Intelligence in Transportation Competition

March 2022 - July 2022

• The aim of the competition was to detect vehicle and human objects using the AI-based object detection system with the camera data of the flying car. We qualified to the semi-finals.

TURKSAT Model Satellite Competition

February 2021 - September 2021

• We competed to launch our satellite with a rocket, safely land it using a brushless motor, and maintain healthy communication with the ground station. We qualified for the finals and finished 11th.

Mechanical Engineering Society Founder

February 2020 - September 2021

• Founded and ran a club named Mechanical Engineering Society in my university.